lain Maitland

Frontend Developer



About

Q USA

(737) 226-3943

iainmaitland.com

imaitland

y iain_maitland

Web Development

Professional

React

Javascript & Typescript

CSS Rust

Languages

English (Native speaker)

Interests

Art

Photography Graphic Design Painting Poetry Writing

Summary

I am a frontend web developer with five years of professional experience. Before going freelance, I worked as an early employee for Steem, building user-facing apps and backend micro-services, with React on their blockchain as it scaled to 1M+ users. I have been learning Rust more recently, using it to make a static site generator. I am excited by any opportunity to use Rust's powerful features in production, particularly when it can complement my experience with Typescript and React.

Experience

Freelance 05/2020 - Present

Develop useful software for a variety of clients Fullstack developer

Working as a lead developer with a local and remote team of graphic and product designers to implement creative and b2b software briefs for a range of clients, including General Motors.

- https://hobbes.work a portfolio site for a UI/UX studio using a modern Jamstack, a customized headless CMS, and a React/Typescript frontend
- https://means.tv a media streaming platform with subscription features
- https://psilabs.org laboratory process tracking software and web front end, so customers can track their samples and publicize test results.
- A custom CRM for General Motors in React and NodeJS used at Dealerships and special events nationwide.

Steemit.com 03/2018 - 05/2020

Developed applications for the Steem blockchain Fullstack Developer

Worked as part of a remote agile team with 3 other developers, to develop and scale open source blockchain software (https://github.com/steemit) used by millions of users and processing millions of dollars in cryptocurrency transactions.

- Built the most popular frontend (React/Typescript) for the Steem blockchain, including authorization, market trading, and cryptocurrency wallet features
- https://steemit.com A reddit clone written in React, scaling from a few thousand to millions of users internationally
- https://signup.steemit.com/ User creation service or 'faucet,' onboarded more than a million new users
- https://wallet.steemit.com Feature-rich cryptocurrency wallet including trading, exchange and withdrawal

Quikly 05/2017 - 03/2018

Developed an administration dashboard in React Frontend Developer

Worked as lead React developer as part of an agile team on b2b dashboard software.

- Build out a GraphQL api in Ruby-on-rails to drive the react frontend
- Advocate for Typescript adoption within the company

Penske Media Corporation

01/2016 - 05/2017

Developed CMSs and frontends for magazines like rollingstone.com and variety.com Frontend Developer

Worked as part of an agile team with 2 other developers, developed CMS backends in Contentful, Wordpress and Drupal and frontends in React

• Lead pivot from traditional CMS instances to a headless model

Education

University of Cambridge, Jesus College